having been shipped across the world
from New Zealand The Specialist
geotextile mats webbing and sandbags
arrive in the UK and are taken out of
their
containers the base of the Sur reath is
formed from three separate sections the
materials are triple stitched together
to form each
section
the bags are attached to the reef
webbing base with over 1,000
ties the first section of the reef base
layer is approximately the size of a
football pitch it is consoled up to make
transporting it
easier and then placed on a barge the
section weighs 10 tons and so lifting is
a delicate process when sea conditions
are absolutely flat and perfect the
barge travels to bosam the site of the
reef just 250 M from boson Beach
Shoreline the first section of the reef
is slowly deployed onto the seabed the
barge travels slowly along the reef site
allowing the section to gradually unfold
into the water divers then attach the
webbing straps to huge anchors on the
seabed to secure its position the bags
are then filled one by one with careful
y refined sand which has been harvested
on boson
Beach a 300 M pipeline transports the
sand out to sea where divers attach the
pipes to the bags filling each bag takes
between 1 and 4 hours and can only be
done during perfect weather and tidal
conditions don't forget to visit this
site to keep up toate with the latest
news about the
reef